Guide to the Kirsten Flagstad Collection
Kirsten Flagstad collection,
- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Selections, Act 1, Part 21956560105 M1, 560105 M3, 560105 M4, 560108, 560110, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 4, Folder 5601052)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Svanholm, Set; Fjeldstad, Øivin; Filharmoniske selskap (Oslo, Norway); Norsk rikskringkasting orkester; Norsk rikskringkasting. Recording: Recorded from the Norwegian State Broadcasting System, Oslo, January 5, 1956. Includes introductory remarks in several languages, including English.Continues 56015 M1 and continued by 560105 M3--M4, 560108 M1--M3, 560110 M1--M3.
- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Selections. Act 1, Part 31956560105 M1, 560105 M2, 560105 M4, 560108, 560110, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 4, Folder 5601053)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Svanholm, Set; Fjeldstad, Øivin; Filharmoniske selskap (Oslo, Norway); Norsk rikskringkasting orkester; Norsk rikskringkasting. Recording: Recorded from the Norwegian State Broadcasting System, Oslo, January 5, 1956. Includes introductory remarks in several languages, including English.Continues 560105 M1--M2 and continued by 560105 M4, 560108 M1--M3, 560110 M1--M3.
- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Selections, Act 1, Part 41956560105 M1, 560105 M2, 560105 M3, 560108, 560110, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 4, Folder 5601054)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Svanholm, Set; Fjeldstad, Øivin; Filharmoniske selskap (Oslo, Norway); Norsk rikskringkasting orkester; Norsk rikskringkasting. Recording: Recorded from the Norwegian State Broadcasting System, Oslo, January 5, 1956. Includes introductory remarks in several languages, including English.ncludes introductory remarks in several languages, including English. Continues 560105 M1--M3 and continued by 560108 M1--M3, 560110 M1--M3.
- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Selections, Act 2, Part 11956560105, 560108 M2, 560108 M3, 560110, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 4, Folder 5601081)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Svanholm, Set; Fjeldstad, Øivin; Filharmoniske selskap (Oslo, Norway); Norsk rikskringkasting orkester; Norsk rikskringkasting. Recording: Recorded from the Norwegian State Broadcasting System, Oslo, January 5, 1956. Includes introductory remarks in several languages, including English.Includes introductory remarks in several languages, including English. Continues 560105 M1--M4 and continued by 560108 M2--M3, 560110 M1--M3.
- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Selections Act 2, Part 21956560105, 560108 M1, 560108 M3, 560110, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 4, Folder 5601082)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Svanholm, Set; Fjeldstad, Øivin; Filharmoniske selskap (Oslo, Norway); Norsk rikskringkasting orkester; Norsk rikskringkasting. Recording: Recorded from the Norwegian State Broadcasting System, Oslo, January 5, 1956. Includes introductory remarks in several languages, including English.Continues 560105 M1--M4 and 560108 M1 and continued by 560108 M3, 560110 M1--M3.
- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Selections, Act 2, Part 31956560105, 560108 M1, 560108 M2, 560110, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 4, Folder 5601083)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Svanholm, Set; Fjeldstad, Øivin; Filharmoniske selskap (Oslo, Norway); Norsk rikskringkasting orkester; Norsk rikskringkasting. Recording: Recorded from the Norwegian State Broadcasting System, Oslo, January 5, 1956. Includes introductory remarks in several languages, including English.Includes introductory remarks in several languages, including English. Continues 560105 M1--M4 and 560108 M1--M2 and continued by 560110 M1--M3
- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Selections, Act 3, Part 11956560105, 560108, 560110 M2, 560110 M3, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 4, Folder 5601101)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Svanholm, Set; Fjeldstad, Øivin; Filharmoniske selskap (Oslo, Norway); Norsk rikskringkasting orkester; Norsk rikskringkasting. Recording: Recorded from the Norwegian State Broadcasting System, Oslo, January 5, 1956. Includes introductory remarks in several languages, including English.Continues 560105 M1--M4 and 560108 M1--M3 and continued by 560110 M2--M3.
- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Selections, Act 3, Part 21956560105, 560108, 560110 M1, 560110 M3, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 4, Folder 5601102)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Svanholm, Set; Fjeldstad, Øivin; Filharmoniske selskap (Oslo, Norway); Norsk rikskringkasting orkester; Norsk rikskringkasting. Recording: Recorded from the Norwegian State Broadcasting System, Oslo, January 5, 1956. Includes introductory remarks in several languages, including English.Continues 560105 M1--M4, 560108 M1--M3 and 560110 M1 and continued by 560110 M3.
- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Selections, Act 3, Part 31956560105, 560108, 560110 M1, 560110 M2, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 4, Folder 5601103)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Svanholm, Set; Fjeldstad, Øivin; Filharmoniske selskap (Oslo, Norway); Norsk rikskringkasting orkester; Norsk rikskringkasting. Recording: Recorded from the Norwegian State Broadcasting System, Oslo, January 5, 1956. Includes introductory remarks in several languages, including English.Includes introductory remarks in several languages, including English. Continues 560105 M1--M4, 560108 M1--M3 and 560110 M1--M2.
- Karen-Marie Flagstad and Kirsten Flagstad--Diverse performances1938-1949, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono., Full Range FR-7; 7 in. (Box 4, Folder 5602181)
  Performers: Flagstad, Karen-Marie; Svanholm, Set; Böhm, Karl, 1894- Recording: Various songs and opera excerpts sung by Karen-Marie Flagstad and Kirsten Flagstad dating from April 10, 1938-1949. Some recorded from the radio program "The magic key" to disc and then to tape; others recorded from discs. Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. Frühlingsstimmen. English (broadcast 4/10/1938); Edwards, Clara, 1887-1974. By the bend of the river (broadcast 4/10/1938); Gruber, Franz Xaver, 1787-1863. Stille Nacht, heilige Nacht. English (broadcast 12/25/1938); bells of Trinity Church, New York (12/25/1938); Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tristan und Isolde. 1. Aufzug. Selections (broadcast 2/18/1939); Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 10. Allerseelen (with piano); Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Hjertets melodier. Jeg elsker dig; Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. 2 Aufzug. 4. Szene (broadcast 1949).
  Magic key (Radio program); Trinity Church (New York, N.Y.)
- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Lohengrin, Act 1 by Richard Wagner, November, 21, 19381938, 1956, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half-track, mono., Full Range FR-7; 7 in. (Box 4, Folder 5602201)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Maison, René, 1895-1962; Gurney, John, 1902-1997; Lamont, Eleanor; McArthur, Edwin; Chicago Civic Opera (Chicago, Ill.). Recording: NBC Radio broadcast. Announcements in English. Recorded from the air to disc, November 21, 1938 and then to tape, February 20, 1956.
- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Selections.1937, 1956, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., BASF TYP LGS; 7 in. (Box 4, Folder 56000014)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; other performers unknown. Recording: Re-recorded from disc of 1937 performance in 1956.
- Aarhunredets stemme = Voice of the century. Part 1April 13, 1957570413 M2, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 190A-18-100G; 7 in. (Box 5, Folder 5704131)
  Performers: Hegermann-Lindencrøne, Knud; Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Alme, Waldemar. Recording: from Danish Radio, April 13, 1957. Knud Hegermann-Lindencrøne speaking in Danish about Kirsten Flagstad. Continued on 570413 M2. Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Walkürenritt; Alnæs, Eyvind, 1872-1932. Sange, op. 26. Lykken mellem to mennesker; Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Brünnhildes Schlussgesang; Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tristan und Isolde. O sink' hernieder; Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Matthäuspassion. Erbarme dich, erbarme dich, mein Gott
  Danmarks radio
- Aarhunredets stemme = Voice of the century. Part 2; TodesverkündungApril 13, 1957570413 M1, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 190A-18-100G; 7 in. (Box 5, Folder 5704132)
  Performers: Hegermann-Lindencrøne, Knud; Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Alme, Waldemar. Recording: from Danish Radio, April 13, 1957. Knud Hegermann-Lindencrøne speaking in Danish about Kirsten Flagstad. Continues 570413 M1. Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Alme, Waldemar; Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Haugtussa. Killingdans -- Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 10. Zueignung -- Purcell, Henry, 1659-1695. Dido and Aeneas. When I am laid in earth -- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Walküre. Siegmund! Sieh auf mich
- Gluck, Christoph Willibald, Ritter von, 1714-1787. Alceste (1776), Act IIApril 14, 1957570414 M2, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 190A-18-100G; 7 in. (Box 5, Folder 5704141)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; unknown performers. Recording: Broadcast from Danish Radio April 14, 1957. Act III is recorded on 570414 M2.
- Gluck, Christoph Willibald, Ritter von, 1714-1787. Alceste (1776), Act III.April 14, 1957570414 M1, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 190A-18-100G; 7 in. (Box 5, Folder 5704142)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; unknown performers. Recording: Broadcast from Danish Radio April 14, 1957. Act II is recorded on 570414 M1.
- Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Zauberflöte. Norwegian1958?580000 M2, 580000 M3, 580000 M4, 580000 M5, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A-12; 7 in. (Box 5, Folder 5800001)
  Performers: Norske opera (?) Recording: Kirsten Flagstad does not sing in this performance, so it is likely the tape is from the Norwegian National Opera when Kirsten Flagstad was director (1958-1960). Continued by 580000 M2--M5
- Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Zauberflöte. Norwegian1958?580000 M1, 580000 M3, 580000 M4, 580000 M5, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A-12; 7 in. (Box 5, Folder 5800002)
  Performers: Norske opera (?) Recording: Kirsten Flagstad does not sing in this performance, so it is likely the tape is from the Norwegian National Opera when Kirsten Flagstad was director (1958-1960). Continues 580000 M1 and is continued by 580000 M3--M5
- Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Zauberflöte. Norwegian1958?580000 M1, 580000 M2, 580000 M4, 580000 M5, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A-12; 7 in. (Box 5, Folder 5800003)
  Performers: Norske opera (?) Recording: Kirsten Flagstad does not sing in this performance, so it is likely the tape is from the Norwegian National Opera when Kirsten Flagstad was director (1958-1960). Continues 580000 M1--M2 and is continued by 580000 M4--M5.
- Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Zauberflöte. Norwegian1958?580000 M1, 580000 M2, 580000 M3, 580000 M5, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A-12; 7 in. (Box 5, Folder 5800004)
  Performers: Norske opera (?) Recording: Kirsten Flagstad does not sing in this performance, so it is likely the tape is from the Norwegian National Opera when Kirsten Flagstad was director (1958-1960). Continues 580000 M1--M3 and is continued by 580000 M5.
- Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Zauberflöte. Norwegian1958?580000 M1, 580000 M2, 580000 M3, 580000 M4, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A-12; 7 in. (Box 5, Folder 5800005)
  Performers: Norske opera (?) Recording: Kirsten Flagstad does not sing in this performance, so it is likely the tape is from the Norwegian National Opera when Kirsten Flagstad was director (1958-1960). Continues 580000 M1--M4.
- Lauritz Melchior: der kaarede [?] WagnersängerJul. 11, 1958, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 5, Folder 5807111)
  Performers: Hegermann-Lindencrøne, Knud, narrator; Melchior, Lauritz; Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Leider, Frida, 1888-1975; Bockelmann, Rudolf; Janssen, Herbert. Recording: Program from Danish Radio on Lauritz Melchior with musical excerpts Die Walküre (with Lotte Lehmann); Siegfried (with Albert Reiss); Götterdämmerung (with Otto Helgers); Tristan und Isolde (with Frida Leider, Kirsten Flagstad, Rudolf Bockelman and Herbert Janssen).
  Melchior, Lauritz
- Johansen, David Monrad, 1888- Nordlands trompetAug. 21, 1958, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 5, Folder 5808211)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Alme, Waldemar, piano; Dass, Petter, 1647-1708, lyrics. Recording: Copied from oo 31239 [?].
- Haarklou, Johannes, 1847-1925. Songs. Selections1958, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo., Scotch no. 111 A-P; 7 in. (Box 5, Folder 5808291)
  Performers: Alme, Waldemar; Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962. Recording: Copied from oo 7537 [?]. Haarklou, Johannes, 1847-1925. Tora synger; Hurd suser natten; Sange til Tekster af Knut Hamsun. Med röde rosen; Mainat; Minde.
- Borgstrøm, Hjalmar, 1864-1925. Songs. SelectionsSept. 4, 1958, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, stereo., Scotch no. 111 A-12; 7 in. (Box 5, Folder 5809041)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Alme, Waldemar; Borgstrøm, Hjalmar, 1864-1925. Salomo I; Salomo II; Storme; Til min mor; Wer von Einst'ger Liebe spricht; Geständnis; Meine Haft ging
- Ollie & Buck (Radio program)Feb. 7, 1959, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono., Scotch no. 190A-18-100G; 7 in. (Box 5, Folder 5902071)
  Ollie & Buck, unidentified singer and pianist and others talking and caricaturing various vocal styles and "singing" songs. 4 unidentified and improvised caricatures.
  Wit and humor, Musical
- Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Preludes, piano, op. 28. Selections; Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957. Morceaux, piano, op. 75. GranenJuly 12, 1960, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono., Scotch 311-12; 5 in. (Box 6, Folder 6007121)
  Performers: Waldemar Alme, piano. Between the two piano works is a 65th birthday greeting to Kirsten Flagstad from Alme.
- Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Songs. Selections. Norwegian & German1923-1936, 1961, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono., Audiotape type 1251; 7 in. (Box 6, Folder 6100001)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; unknown pianist; unknown orchestra. Recording: Originally recorded between 1923 and 1936, and re-recorded from discs in 1961. Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Peer Gynt. Solvejgs sang; Romancer, op. 15. Modersorg; Romancer (ældre og nyere). Millom rosor (with orchestra) -- Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Hjertets melodier. Jeg elsker dig; Hjertets melodier. Jeg elsker dig. German; Lieder, op. 48. Traum; Lieder, op. 48. Traum. Norwegian; Digte, op. 25. Svane. German; Digte af Vilhelm Krag. Mens jeg venter; Digte af Otto Benzon, op. 70. Lys nat (with piano)
- Songs by Norwegian composers1923-1936, 1961, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono., Audiotape type 1251; 7 in. (Box 6, Folder 6100002)
  Perfomers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; unknown orchestra; unknown pianist. Recording: Originally recorded between 1923 and 1936, and re-recorded from discs in 1961. Bull, Ole, 1810-1880. Sæterjentens søndag (1923) (with orchestra) -- Sinding, Christian, 1856-1941. Galmandssange. Mainat (1929) (with orchestra) -- Backer-Grøndahl, Agathe, 1847-1907. Barnets vårdag. Mot kvæld (1929) (with orchestra) -- Lie, Sigurd, 1871-1904 (1929). Sne (with piano) -- Alnæ;s, Eyvind, 1872-1932. Sange, op. 26. Lykken mellem to mennesker (2 recordings, 1929 and 1936) (with piano) -- Hurum, Alf, 1882-1972. Blonde netter (1936) (with piano).
- Songs by American composers and by Dvorák1936-1937, 1961, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono., Audiotape type 1251; 7 in. (Box 6, Folder 6100003)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; unknown pianist. Recording: Originally recorded between 1936 and 1937, and re-recorded from discs in 1961. Kernochan, Marshall, 1880-1955. We two together -- Worth, Bobby, 1921- Midsummer -- Ronald, Landon, Sir, 1873-1938. Summertime. O lovely night -- Scott, Cyril, 1879-1970. Songs, op. 57. Lullaby -- Dvorák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Cigánské melodie. Kdy mne stará matka. English -- Charles, Ernest, 1895-1984. When I have sung my songs -- Bridge, Frank, 1879-1941. Love went a-riding -- Rogers, James H. (James Hotchkiss), 1857-1940. At parting.
- Songs by Strauss, Beethoven, Brahms and Franz1936-1950, 1961, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono., BASF standard; 7 in. (Box 6, Folder 6100004)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; unknown pianist; unknown violist. Recording: Originally recorded between 1936 and 1950, and re-recorded from discs in 1961. The first 7 songs are with piano accompaniment; the rest are with viola and piano accompaniment. Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 27. Cäcilie (1936); Lieder, op. 17. Seitdem dein Aug' in meines schaute (1937); Lieder, op. 10. Allerseelen (1937); Schlichte Weisen. Ach Lieb, ich muss nun scheiden (1936) -- Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Lieder, op. 48. Ehre Gottes aus der Natur (1936); Zärtliche Liebe (1936) -- Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Lieder und Gesänge, op. 63. Junge Lieder, no. 1 (1936); Gesänge, viola, piano acc., op. 91. Gestillte Sehnsucht (1950); Gesänge, viola, piano acc., op. 91. Geistliches Wiegenlied (1950) -- Franz, Robert, 1815-1892. Gesänge, op. 17. Im Herbst (1937).
- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Songs. Selections1936-1950, 1961, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono., Audiotape type 1251; 7 in. (Box 6, Folder 6100005)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; unknown pianist. Recording: Originally recorded between 1936 and 1950, and re-recorded from discs in 1961. Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Ellens Gesang, D. 839 (1936); Forelle (Song) (1937); Lachen und Weinen (1937); Im Abendrot (1950); Frühlingsglaube (1950); Du bist die Ruh (1950); Allmacht (Song) (1950)
- Songs by Handel, Bizet, Bach, Löhner, Franck and Carissimi.1948-1950, 1961, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono., BSF standard; 7 in. (Box 6, Folder 6100006)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; unknown orchestra; unknown pianist. Recording: Originally recorded between 1948 and 1950, and re-recorded from discs in 1961. Dank sei dir Herr (1948) (with orchestra) -- Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Serse. Ombra mai fù (1948) (with orchestra) -- Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875. Arlésienne. Intermezzo; arr. (1948) (with orchestra) -- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Matthäuspassion. Erbarme dich, erbarme dich, mein Gott (1950) (with orchestra); Komm, süsser Tod (1950) (with piano) -- Löhner, Johann, 1645-1705. O, Ewigkeit (1950) (with piano) -- Franck, Johann Wolfgang, ca. 1644-ca. 1710. Sie nur still (1950) (with piano) -- Franck, Johann Wolfgang, ca. 1644-ca. 1710. Auf, auf, zu Gottes lob (1950) (with piano) -- Carissimi, Giacomo, 1605-1674. Soccoretemi (1950) (with piano)
- Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Songs. Selections. II1936-1948, 1961, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono., Audiotape type 1251; 7 in. (Box 6, Folder 6100007)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; unknown pianist; unknown orchestra. Recording: Originally recorded between 1936 and 1948, and re-recorded from discs in 1961. Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Digte af Otto Benzon, op. 69. Gynger en båd på bølge (1946); Digte af John Paulsen. Håb (1936); Digte af John Paulsen. Med en primula veris (1937); Digte af Vilhelm Krag. Og jeg vil ha mig en hjertenskjaer (1937); Prinsessen (1948); Digte, op. 25. Med en vandlilje (1948); Melodier til digte af A.O. Vinje. Fyremål (1948); Romancer og sange, op. 18. Efteraarsstormen (1948); Digte af Otto Benzon, op. 70. Eros (1948); Digte, op. 25. Svane (1948)
- Waldemar Alme performs piano music of Grieg, Palmgren, Sibelius and Chopin1950-1961, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono., Scotch; 7 in. (Box 6, Folder 6108001)
  Performers: Alme, Waldemar. Recording: Grieg taped August, 1961; Palmgren recorded 1950; Sibelius taped June 1960; Chopin recorded 1950. Has announcements by the performer. Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Lyriske stykker, op. 43. Sommerfugl; Lyriske stykker, op. 62. Bækken; Lyriske stykker, op. 54. Notturno; Lyriske stykker, op. 68. Aften på højfjeldet; Lyriske stykker, op. 71. Småtrold; Norske folkeviser. Kulok; Norske folkeviser. I Ola-dalom, i Ola-kjønn; Slåtter. Jon Vestafes springdans; Improvisata over to norske folkeviser -- Palmgren, Selim, 1878-1951. Preludes, piano, op. 17. Meri -- Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957. Morceaux, piano, op. 75. Granen -- Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Preludes, piano, op. 28. Selections -- Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Spiewy polskie; Sonatas, piano, no. 2, op. 35, B? minor. Finale; Impromptus, piano, ?
- Interview with Torstein Gunnarson; Mahler, Gustav, 1860-1911. KindertotenliederOct. 25, 1961, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono., Scotch no. 111-12; 7 in. (Box 6, Folder 6110251)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Boult, Adrian, Sir, 1889-; Gunnarson, Torstein; Vienna Philharmonia Orchestra
- Kirsten Flagstad in conversation with Torstein Gunnarson, Part 1Dec. 2, 1961611202 S2, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono., Scotch no. 111-12; 7 in. (Box 6, Folder 6112021)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Gunnarson, Torstein Recording: Recorded December 2, 1961. Continued by 611202 S2. Kirsten Flagstad interviewed by Torstein Gunnarson in a Scandinavian language. Mostly autobiographical with musical examples.
- Kirsten Flagstad in conversation with Torstein Gunnarson, Part 21961611202 S1, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono., Scotch no. 111-12; 7 in. (Box 6, Folder 6112022)
  Performers: Flagstad, Kirsten, 1895-1962; Gunnarson, Torstein. Recording: Recorded December 2, 1961. Continues 611202 S1. Kirsten Flagstad interviewed by Torstein Gunnarson in a Scandinavian language. Mostly autobiographical with musical examples.
- Gift from Kir and Nancy to Kirsten, Else, Arthur and Sigurd, December 1, 1962Dec. 1, 1962, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono., Scotch no. 190-18; 7 in. (Box 6, Folder 6212011)